<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>

    <title>ODB News</title>
    <link>http://www.codesynthesis.com/products/odb/</link>
    <copyright>Copyright 2005-2022, Code Synthesis Tool CC</copyright>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <description>News feed for ODB - object-relational mapping (ORM) system for C++</description>
    <managingEditor>boris@codesynthesis.com</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>webmaster@codesynthesis.com</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2016 10:01:16 GMT</lastBuildDate>

    <item>
      <title>ODB 2.4.0 for RHEL, Fedora</title>
      <link>http://www.codesynthesis.com/pipermail/odb-users/2015-July/002657.html</link>
      <description>
        ODB 2.4.0 packages are available for stable Fedora and RHEL releases.
      </description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2015 15:18:40 EDT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>ODB in Debian</title>
      <link>http://www.codesynthesis.com/pipermail/odb-announcements/2015/000042.html</link>
      <description>
        Thanks to persistent effort of László Böszörményi, ODB 2.4.0 is
        now packaged for Debian and available in the 'testing' and 'unstable'
        Debian repositories as well as the 'wily' Ubuntu repository. This
        includes the full set of packages: the ODB compiler, the runtimes
        for all the open source databases (MySQL, PostgreSQL, and SQLite) as
        well as both profile libraries (Qt and Boost).
      </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 09:01:58 EDT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>ODB 2.4.0 released</title>
      <link>http://www.codesynthesis.com/pipermail/odb-announcements/2015/000041.html</link>
      <description>
        Major new features in this release include support for bulk operations
        in Oracle and SQL Server, the ability to join and load multiple objects
        with a single SELECT statement execution (object loading views), as well
        as support for calling stored procedures in MySQL and SQL Server. This
        release also adds support for Visual Studio 2013, including project/solution
        files for all the runtime libraries, examples, and tests.
      </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2015 06:59:41 EST</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>ODB packages for RHEL 5, 6 and Fedora 19-21 available</title>
      <link>http://www.codesynthesis.com/pipermail/odb-announcements/2014/000040.html</link>
      <description>
        Thanks to a persistent effort by Dave Johansen, official ODB packages
        are now available for RedHat Enterprise Linux (EL) 5 and 6 (and
        derivatives such as CentOS, Scientific Linux, etc.), as well as Fedora
        19-21.
      </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2014 01:53:32 EST</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>libodb-qt 2.3.1 bugfix released</title>
      <link>http://www.codesynthesis.com/pipermail/odb-announcements/2014/000039.html</link>
      <description>
        A new bugfix release for the Qt ODB profile library (libodb-qt) is now
        available. It removes the dependency on the STL compatibility functions
        in Qt, which may not be available. In other words, this is a portability
        fix and if you are not experiencing any problems with libodb-qt 2.3.0, you
        don't need to upgrade.
      </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2014 23:03:00 EST</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>libodb-pgsql 2.3.1 bugfix released</title>
      <link>http://www.codesynthesis.com/pipermail/odb-announcements/2013/000038.html</link>
      <description>
        A new bugfix release for the PostgreSQL ODB runtime library (libodb-pgsql)
        is now available. It adds a missing include file that affected compilation
        of generated files that contain only views.
      </description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2013 03:15:05 EST</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>ODB 2.3.0 released</title>
      <link>http://www.codesynthesis.com/pipermail/odb-announcements/2013/000037.html</link>
      <description>
        The major new feature in this release is support for database schema
        evolution, including schema and data migration as well as soft object
        model changes. Other important features in version 2.3.0 include
        support for C++11 enum classes as well as object sections which
        provide the ability to split data members of a persistent class
        into independently loaded/updated groups.
      </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2013 05:53:32 EDT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>libodb-sqlite 2.2.3 bugfix released</title>
      <link>http://www.codesynthesis.com/pipermail/odb-announcements/2013/000036.html</link>
      <description>
        New bugfix release for the SQLite ODB runtime library (libodb-sqlite)
        is now available. It adds support for lower versions of SQLite than
        was previously supported. Now ODB supports SQLite 3.3.6 (which is
        found in RHEL5) and later.
      </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2013 05:32:50 EDT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Multiple ODB 2.2.0 bugfixes released</title>
      <link>http://www.codesynthesis.com/pipermail/odb-announcements/2013/000035.html</link>
      <description>
        New bugfix releases for various ODB 2.2.0 components are now
        available: odb-2.2.2 (source and binaries; various bugfixes),
        libodb-2.2.3 (minor bugfixes), libodb-mssql-2.2.1 (fix for a
        bug in the ROWVERSION type handling), libodb-qt-2.2.1 (fix for
        a bug that affects applications using ODB with Qt5 in the
        dynamic multi-database mode), and libodb-boost-2.2.1 (work
        around for the ambiguous name resolution bug in VC++).
      </description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2013 10:10:29 EDT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>libodb-sqlite 2.2.2 bugfix released</title>
      <link>http://www.codesynthesis.com/pipermail/odb-announcements/2013/000034.html</link>
      <description>
        New bugfix release for the SQLite ODB runtime library (libodb-sqlite)
        is now available. It fixes an incorrect export macro in the
        forced_rollback exception. This bug only affects Windows builds.
      </description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2013 12:52:43 EDT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Using ODB on Android guide available</title>
      <link>http://www.codesynthesis.com/pipermail/odb-announcements/2013/000033.html</link>
      <description>
        Peter Wu contributed instructions for using ODB on Android with
        Android NDK.
      </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 07:56:54 EDT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>libodb-sqlite 2.2.1 bugfix released</title>
      <link>http://www.codesynthesis.com/pipermail/odb-announcements/2013/000032.html</link>
      <description>
        New bugfix release for the SQLite ODB runtime library (libodb-sqlite)
        is now available. It adds the odb::sqlite::forced_rollback recoverable
        exception which is thrown if SQLite forces a transaction to roll back.
        This behavior is new to SQLite 3.7.11.
      </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 09:37:57 EDT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>ODB compiler Windows binary 2.2.1 bugfix released</title>
      <link>http://www.codesynthesis.com/pipermail/odb-announcements/2013/000031.html</link>
      <description>
        A new bugfix release for the ODB compiler Windows binary is now
        available. It fixes an issue with shell globbing (that is, the
        expansion of * and ? in file names) when invoked from the Windows
        command prompt.
      </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2013 08:40:10 EST</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>ODB compiler .deb and .rpm packages available</title>
      <link>http://www.codesynthesis.com/pipermail/odb-announcements/2013/000030.html</link>
      <description>
        ODB compiler packages for Debian/Ubuntu and RedHat(Fedora, RHEL,
        CentOS) are now available.
      </description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2013 08:00:37 EST</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>ODB compiler source 2.2.1 bugfix released</title>
      <link>http://www.codesynthesis.com/pipermail/odb-announcements/2013/000029.html</link>
      <description>
        A new bugfix release for the ODB compiler source package is now
        available. It fixes an issue with the libintl.h header when used
        together with GCC that was configured with --disable-nls.
      </description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2013 06:00:35 EST</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>libodb 2.2.2 bugfix released</title>
      <link>http://www.codesynthesis.com/pipermail/odb-announcements/2013/000028.html</link>
      <description>
        New bugfix release for the common ODB runtime library (libodb) is
        now available. It fixes an issue in queries when used with dynamic
        multi-database support.
      </description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2013 05:53:34 EST</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Gentoo packages for ODB 2.2.0</title>
      <link>http://www.codesynthesis.com/pipermail/odb-announcements/2013/000027.html</link>
      <description>
        Hugo Mildenberger has packaged the complete ODB 2.2.0 system for
        Gentoo and submitted the request for inclusion into the official
        Gentoo repository.
      </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2013 03:00:15 EST</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>libodb 2.2.1 bugfix released</title>
      <link>http://www.codesynthesis.com/pipermail/odb-announcements/2013/000026.html</link>
      <description>
        New bugfix releases for the common ODB runtime library (libodb) is
        now available. It fixes an issue with a missing windows.hxx header
        file and only affects a very specific configuration: installed
        MinGW-W64 builds with the GCC compiler that uses the POSIX
        threading model (run gcc -v). Any other platform or configuration
        is not affected and no upgrade is necessary.
      </description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 10:58:23 EST</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>ODB 2.2.0 released</title>
      <link>http://www.codesynthesis.com/pipermail/odb-announcements/2013/000025.html</link>
      <description>
        Major new features in this release include multi-database support,
        prepared queries, change-tracking containers, custom sessions, and
        automatic mapping for char[N]. This version also adds support for
        Qt5 in addition to Qt4 and now comes with a guide on using ODB with
        mobile/embedded systems.
      </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2013 06:54:15 EST</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>ODB 2.2.0.a3 available</title>
      <link>http://www.codesynthesis.com/pipermail/odb-announcements/2013/000024.html</link>
      <description>
        The third alpha version for the upcoming ODB 2.2.0 is now available.
      </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2013 10:20:34 EST</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Using ODB on Mobile/Embedded Systems guide available</title>
      <link>http://www.codesynthesis.com/pipermail/odb-announcements/2012/000023.html</link>
      <description>
        We just published a detailed guide on using ODB on mobile/embedded
        systems. It uses Raspberry Pi as a sample target (though other
        targets can be handled with similar steps) and covers topics such
        as cross-compilation, building shared/static libraries, footprint,
        and minimizing the generated code size.
      </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2012 02:52:37 EST</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>ODB 2.2.0.a2 available</title>
      <link>http://www.codesynthesis.com/pipermail/odb-announcements/2012/000022.html</link>
      <description>
        The second alpha version for the upcoming ODB 2.2.0 is now available.
      </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2012 09:12:06 EST</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>ODB 2.1.1 released</title>
      <link>http://www.codesynthesis.com/pipermail/odb-announcements/2012/000021.html</link>
      <description>
        This is a bug fix-only release that fixes a number of issues in
        each database runtime as well as the ODB compiler.
      </description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2012 07:30:47 EST</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>ODB 2.2.0.a1 available</title>
      <link>http://www.codesynthesis.com/pipermail/odb-announcements/2012/000020.html</link>
      <description>
        The first alpha version for the upcoming ODB 2.2.0 is now available.
      </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2012 11:04:18 EST</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>ODB 2.1.0 released</title>
      <link>http://www.codesynthesis.com/pipermail/odb-announcements/2012/000018.html</link>
      <description>
	Major new features in this release include the ability to use
	accessor/modifier functions/expressions to access data members,
	support for virtual data members, the ability to define database
	indexes on data members, as well as support for mapping extended
	database types, such as geospatial types, user-defined types, and
	collections. The profile libraries have also been updated with the
	Boost profile now providing persistence support for the Uuid and
	Multi-Index container libraries while the Qt profile now includes
	the QUuid type. Finally, this release adds support for Visual Studio
	2012 and Clang 3.1. Specifically, all the runtime libraries, examples,
	and tests now come with project/solution files for Visual Studio 2012
	in addition to 2010 and 2008.
      </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2012 05:39:11 EST</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>ODB 2.1.0.a2 available</title>
      <link>http://www.codesynthesis.com/pipermail/odb-announcements/2012/000017.html</link>
      <description>
        The second alpha version for the upcoming ODB 2.1.0 is now available.
      </description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2012 10:14:03 EST</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>ODB 2.1.0.a1 available</title>
      <link>http://www.codesynthesis.com/pipermail/odb-announcements/2012/000016.html</link>
      <description>
        The first alpha version for the upcoming ODB 2.1.0 is now available.
      </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2012 04:40:47 EST</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>ODB runtimes 2.0.1 bugfix released</title>
      <link>http://www.codesynthesis.com/pipermail/odb-announcements/2012/000015.html</link>
      <description>
        New bugfix releases for the common ODB runtime library (libodb)
        and database-specific ODB runtime libraries (libodb-database)
        are now available.

	The new common runtime release works around a VC++ compilation
	bug resulting in ambiguous name lookup in polymorphic-map.hxx:44
	for some databases.

	The new database-specific runtime releases fix a compilation bug
	in polymorphic class hierarchies that are split over multiple
	source files.

	In addition the MySQL runtime release fixes a build problem on
	Fedora 15 and later.
      </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2012 04:05:34 EST</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>ODB compiler source 2.0.1 bugfix released</title>
      <link>http://www.codesynthesis.com/pipermail/odb-announcements/2012/000014.html</link>
      <description>
        A new bugfix release for the ODB compiler source package is now
        available. It fixes an issue with GCC 4.7 which can be built in
        either C or C++ mode. The original 2.0.0 source package was only
        working with GCC built in the C++ mode. This bugfix addresses
        this limitation.
      </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2012 04:49:53 EST</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>ODB 2.0.0 released</title>
      <link>http://www.codesynthesis.com/pipermail/odb-announcements/2012/000013.html</link>
      <description>
        Major new features in this release include support for C++11,
        polymorphism, composite objects ids (composite primary keys),
        and the NULL semantics for composite values. This release has
        also been tested with GCC 4.7 and Clang 3.0 with the ODB compiler
        now supporting the GCC 4.7 series plugin interface. With this
        release we are also introducing a free proprietary license for
        small object models.
      </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2012 04:25:13 EST</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>ODB 1.8.0 released</title>
      <link>http://www.codesynthesis.com/pipermail/odb-announcements/2012/000012.html</link>
      <description>
        Major new features in this release are support for the Microsoft SQL
        Server database, including updates to the Boost and Qt profiles,
        support for database schemas (database namespaces), and the ability to
        define composite value types as C++ class template instantiations.
      </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2012 02:01:03 EST</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>ODB 1.7.0 released</title>
      <link>http://www.codesynthesis.com/pipermail/odb-announcements/2011/000011.html</link>
      <description>
	Major new features in this release are support for the Oracle database,
	including updates to the Boost and Qt profiles, support for optimistic
	concurrency using object versioning, support for read-only/const data
	members, support for persistent classes without object ids, and support
	for SQL statement execution tracing.
      </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2011 01:23:39 EST</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>libodb-qt 1.6.1 bugfix released</title>
      <link>http://www.codesynthesis.com/pipermail/odb-announcements/2011/000010.html</link>
      <description>
         A new bugfix release for the Qt ODB profile library and ODB compiler
         binary packages is now available. It fixes an issue with the QByteArray
         to BLOB mapping that affects Qt versions prior to 4.7.
      </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 1 Nov 2011 09:38:24 EST</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>ODB compiler source 1.6.2 bugfix released</title>
      <link>http://www.codesynthesis.com/pipermail/odb-announcements/2011/000009.html</link>
      <description>
         A new bugfix release for the ODB compiler source package is now
         available. It fixes an issue with plugin include paths in GCC 4.6.
      </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2011 10:41:02 EST</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>ODB compiler source 1.6.1 bugfix released</title>
      <link>http://www.codesynthesis.com/pipermail/odb-announcements/2011/000008.html</link>
      <description>
         A bugfix release for the ODB compiler source package version 1.6.0
         is now available. It fixes an issue with profile path parsing in
         some GCC builds.
      </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2011 06:39:26 EST</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>ODB 1.6.0 released</title>
      <link>http://www.codesynthesis.com/pipermail/odb-announcements/2011/000007.html</link>
      <description>
          The major new feature in this release is the introduction of the
          view concept.  A view is a light-weight, read-only projection of
          one or more persistent objects or database tables or the result
          of a native SQL query execution.  Views can be used to load a
          subset of data members from objects or columns from database
          tables, execute and handle results of arbitrary SQL queries,
          including aggregate queries, as well as join multiple objects
          and/or database tables using object relationships or custom
          join conditions.

          Other important features in this release include support for
          deleting persistent objects using a query expression, support
          for the NULL semantics with mapping to smart pointers,
          odb::nullable, or boost::optional, and support for mapping BLOB
          types to std::vector&lt;char>.
      </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2011 03:59:34 EST</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>ODB 1.5.0 released</title>
      <link>http://www.codesynthesis.com/pipermail/odb-announcements/2011/000006.html</link>
      <description>
          Major new features in this release are support for PostgreSQL,
          including updates to the Boost and Qt profiles, support for
          per-class database operations callbacks, a new NULL handling
          mechanism, as well as the ability to specify database default
          values and additional column definition options.
      </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2011 03:36:24 EST</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>BoostCon 2011 ODB talk</title>
      <link>http://www.codesynthesis.com/pipermail/odb-announcements/2011/000005.html</link>
      <description>
          The video and slides for the "Object-Relational Mapping with ODB
          and Boost" presentation at this year's BoostCon are now available.
      </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2011 05:35:23 EST</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>ODB 1.4.0 released</title>
      <link>http://www.codesynthesis.com/pipermail/odb-announcements/2011/000004.html</link>
      <description>
          Major new features in this release include the Qt profile providing
          persistence support for Qt basic types, date-time types, smart
          pointers, and containers, support for non-polymorphic object
          inheritance including abstract base classes, and automatic mapping
          of C++ enumerations to database ENUM or integer types.
      </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2011 07:44:24 EST</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>ODB 1.3.0 released</title>
      <link>http://www.codesynthesis.com/pipermail/odb-announcements/2011/000003.html</link>
      <description>
          Major new features in this release are support for the SQLite
          database, including the integration of the shared cache and unlock
          notification functionality for multi-threaded applications, as well
          as support for the GCC 4.6 plugin interface.
      </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2011 03:08:36 EST</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>ODB 1.2.0 released</title>
      <link>http://www.codesynthesis.com/pipermail/odb-announcements/2011/000002.html</link>
      <description>
          Major new features in this release include the Boost profile
          providing persistence support for Boost smart pointers, containers,
          and value types, support for embedding database schemas into
          generated C++ code, and support for transparent database
          reconnection.
      </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2011 07:46:28 EST</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>ODB 1.1.0 released</title>
      <link>http://www.codesynthesis.com/pipermail/odb-announcements/2011/000001.html</link>
      <description>
          Major new features in this release include support for containers,
          composite (multi-column) value types, unidirectional and bidirectional
          object relationships with support for lazy loading, custom object
          pointers, object caching, as well as native SQL statement execution.
      </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2011 04:37:28 EST</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>ODB 1.0.0 released</title>
      <link>http://www.codesynthesis.com/pipermail/odb-announcements/2010/000000.html</link>
      <description>
          ODB is an open-source, compiler-based object-relational mapping (ORM)
          system for C++. It allows you to persist C++ objects to a relational
          database without having to deal with tables, columns, or SQL and
          without manually writing any mapping code.
      </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2010 10:13:42 EST</pubDate>

    </item>

  </channel>
</rss>
